<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Catalyst Eastern Town Hall – Fund 8 Challenges</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/</link><description>Recent content in Fund 8 Challenges on Catalyst Eastern Town Hall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/catalyst/fund8/challenges/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catalyst: Accelerate Decentralized Identity</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/accelerate-decentralized-idenity/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/accelerate-decentralized-idenity/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/11-Accelerate-Decentralized-Identity-83a0b3.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383978">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26443/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What solutions can we develop and implement with Atala PRISM to have the most positive impact and opportunities for rapid growth of Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By identifying high-value credentials, we can establish governance framework foundries for launching pilot programs and driving growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Discover repeatable patterns that unlock our ability to leverage the Cardano decentralized infrastructure. Identify high-value credentials.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The sum of realized production pilots or launches in 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discovery of repeatable patterns in use-cases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The number of issuers, holders, and verifiers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The number of verifications performed on credentials in production&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our challenge is an evolution of the mass decentralized identity (DID) adoption challenge from Funding Round 6, connecting everything we are learning with the first Atala PRISM Pioneer Program cohort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second cohort of the Atala PRISM Pioneer Program will kick off once Catalyst Fund 7 is complete. Between now and then, any member of the Catalyst Community inspired to write a proposal will get access to the Atala PRISM Pioneer Program first cohort course materials on Canvas. Please submit your proposal on Ideascale, including your email address, to get an invitation to Canvas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this access, you&amp;rsquo;ll join the growing Atala PRISM community. Our Atala PRISM product team and engineers will be available via a dedicated Discord channel. Inclusion in our Professional Services Group governance framework foundry. Access to fireside chats with the top leaders in the SSI space, where we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss trends, use cases, and much more. In addition, we will support the growth of high-value credentials and enable partners from concept, to development, to commercialization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="areas-of-focus">Areas of Focus&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="interoperability">Interoperability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Most digital credentials sit on Hyperledger Indy ledgers, including those issued by governments in Germany, Canada, and the UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best-performing platform will gain the largest market share. For many reasons, we believe our platform is superior. Therefore, Cardano and Atala PRISM must include a plan to interact with these other ecosystems to maximize market share.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We encourage Catalyst proposals to achieve full interoperability. Deliverables should optimize the user experience (UX) for Atala PRISM credentials while remaining compatible with other platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="self-governance-of-emergent-communities">Self-governance of Emergent Communities&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="dao-governance-in-practice">DAO Governance in Practice&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>New legislation in Wyoming allows for a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) to be registered with the state. We challenge the community to establish a DAO under the new laws. It could manage an impact or development goal with shared common resources governed by the DAO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are curious to see if our community proposes a DAO. With a funded proposal, we could facilitate introductions to legal experts in Wyoming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The proposal should consider setting aside funds for legal expenses to establish the DAO and legal documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="patterns-of-commoning">Patterns of Commoning&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>We draw inspiration from the work of the Trust Over IP Foundation and the principles from &amp;lsquo;Patterns of Commoning.&amp;rsquo; We see the potential for innovation by linking communities with shared interests under these principles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How can these principles become plug-and-play code as technological primitives that other communities can leverage and unlock exponential growth and adoption?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are interested in exploring a rich playground of ideas and bringing these to real-world implementations on Cardano and Atala PRISM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="education-career-and-emergent-reputation-primitives">Education, Career, and Emergent Reputation Primitives&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Many of our Pioneer and Catalyst-funded projects support education and career programs. One of the defining characteristics of these approaches is the creation of alternatives to accredited education and career paths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need our community to think about developing technology and governance primitives to support any community that wants to establish new education and career paths by providing tools:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For onboarding new experts and teachers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For people in the community to develop and grow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For maintaining a reputation as a skilled employee, laborer, consultant, mentor, teacher, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When reputation standards change, we need ways to self-heal and self-monitor for bad actors, harmful actions, or bad outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Circular Supply Chain&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The global supply chain focuses on creating a new economic infrastructure. The goal is replacing or integrating with legacy systems such as record-keeping, bills of lading, centrally managed systems of record, and distribution networks. Centralization has many challenges, the least of which is a lack of resilience in the global supply chain, as we have all seen and continue to experience in the COVID era.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Supply chains tend to start as decentralized. Markets and trade routes emerge from the bottom of the producer market and are aggregated into centralized supply chains, eventually working their way down to the consumer. We want to explore new patterns of commerce in bottom-up supply chains that could open and expand the local reputation network into markets that are currently inaccessible, such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerative agriculture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Locally produced art&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other forms of local commerce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>On the other side, distribution or demand-driven commerce has the potential to build a market force from the bottom-up that can engage the industrial global supply chain in ways that are not possible without establishing the voice and economic strength of the community digitally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the supply chain challenge, we want to address two significant challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="small-producer-problem">Small Producer Problem&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>How can we create transparency as the bottom-up process meets the industrialized supply chains, cuts through the centralized distribution markets, and connects directly to the consumer?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, small producers like a family ranch in Wyoming have no way to get information about the value of their product through these global aggregation and distribution networks. Currently, a solution such as the BeefChain project is supporting small ranchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are multiple issues to overcome. For example, packaging plants are the entry point to the aggregation, so there is little or no incentive to deal with the small producer. We want to address this problem by building general-purpose tooling to assist communities in self-organizing and self-governing production according to agreed standards. We propose that if these communities can connect and grow, they will either:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reach the market through alternative distribution channels to industrial supply chains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be able to negotiate as a community for better terms to have the values of their products recognized, distributed, and sold with value intact commercially and reputationally.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="the-last-mile-problem">The Last-Mile Problem&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>How can a local distributor in a local market interact with global industrial supply chains and be given access to the market that otherwise would be inaccessible due to a lack of economic identity or capital to access the goods at the scale required by industrial supply chains?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This challenge deals with distributing necessary products to local communities with little market clout or access to financial tools, such as credit, to interact with the industrial supply chain. We&amp;rsquo;re looking for bottom-up tooling to establish a network of communities. Delegates in those communities can access the finance and credit necessary to interact with the industrial supply chain at the economic scale required for transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An example of this problem is delivering health care supplies to rural and developing countries and economies. The funds from donors, the government, and other sources are available for these medical supplies. The donors will only release the funds once delivery is verified, and the medical supply companies will only send the goods to port once payment is received.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, local small businesses must maintain transparency and oversight of the goods during delivery and receiving. These businesses do not have the funds or the ability to borrow capital to cover medical supplies costs from the delivery at the port to the hospitals and clinics that need them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addressing the challenge of the financial gap is vital. We believe that there is enormous potential to create bottom-up networks of trusted individuals and small businesses to fill this gap.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="a-proposed-pattern-language-outline-example">A Proposed Pattern Language Outline (example)&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primitives&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Digital Identity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verifiable Credential (VC)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verifiable Presentation Request&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verifiable Presentation Proof&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cryptocurrency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Non-fungible token (NFT)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Smart contract&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Patterns&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Trust Registry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Governance Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Token Curated Registry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community member recognition and onboarding process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establishing Individual Reputation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community as a whole group Interaction with an external party&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community member as an individual interaction with an external party&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community medium of exchange&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Recognition of external Trust Registry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Recognition of external Governance Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Acceptance of Governance Framework by an external party&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With that as background, we are suggesting proposals in the following three areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Interoperability between Cardano and Indy anchored DIDs/VCs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Self-governance of Emergent Communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Circular Supply Chain&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Business Solutions B2B &amp; B2C</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/business-solutions-b2b-b2c/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/business-solutions-b2b-b2c/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/13-Business-Solutions-B2B--B2C-7b4b0f.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>1,000,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/382660">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26445/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can Cardano-based solutions help meet real business needs and what would be their impact?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Companies are finally discovering the power of blockchain technologies and Cardano is ready to onboard exciting B2B and B2C solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Innovative products and services that increase efficiency, transparency, and stakeholder engagement as well as expand business to new areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>of Cardano dApps supporting business solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of existing companies proposing Cardano-based solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of partnerships,joint ventures created between companies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>additional funding from other sources for the funded proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>projected cost savings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>projected revenue increase&lt;/li>
&lt;li>growth in mainnet &amp;amp; testnet activity due to business solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For years blockchain has held a promise that has not been properly filled. Spot solutions for e.g. traceability, supply chain management, identification and payments have been implemented but large scale benefits of this promising technology are yet to be seen. Based on years of rigorous research and development, Cardano is one of the most serious contenders to fulfill this promise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent and upcoming technological developments in Cardano—smart contracts, Yoroi dApp connector, larger block size (higher throughput), sidechains and state channels, to name a few—are gearing Cardano to be ready for large scale adoption in 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Large corporations, small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs), platform businesses and highly networked startups have very different types of needs. Their industries may vary from finance and high-tech to agriculture and construction and from simple services to knowledge-intensive business. Yet, at the end of the day, they all need modern tools to keep fulfilling their mission, to remain relevant in global competition and to offer their employees the best tools to do what they were hired to do. Any company wants to engage their partners and employees, serve their customers better, improve their processes, cut costs, increase revenues and expand to new business areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By removing the middle man and automating processes, smart contract blockchain solutions can drive all of the above. Cardano can at least partly answer to these needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In this challenge, proposed solutions can be tools, services, products, process improvements, data management solutions (CRM, ERP, MES, DMP etc), decentralized cloud solutions, privacy and security related offerings or even metaverse-related solutions.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In your proposal, it would be good to outline the extent, limits and scope of the solution readiness-level of the solution, and whether it is e.g:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A Feasibility Study, Proof-of-Concept, Minimum Viable Product that could be built on Cardano.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An existing business-ready product or service that could be converted to run on Cardano.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A business-oriented training or consultancy service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An existing blockchain solution brought into the Cardano ecosystem to serve business needs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A prototype or demo in operational environment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A creation of model of a system or subsystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A process improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When submitting proposals, please include the long-term vision, strategy and roadmap as well as short-term deliverables attainable in the next 6-9 months. Visualization and video materials are more than welcome to explain often complex business solutions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Cardano Scaling Solutions</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/cardano-scaling-solutions/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/cardano-scaling-solutions/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/05-Cardano-scaling-solutions-7a0e11.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>400,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383094">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26437/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What research and scaling implementations can be introduced to help Cardano increase scalability?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hydra will not solve every scaling problem in Cardano, more scaling solutions are needed as alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Scaling solutions that are introduced and implemented by the community that Cardano projects can start using.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of scaling solutions available to the community to use within their projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of projects launched on any of the new scaling solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Novel ideas generated from research on different scaling approaches&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For Cardano to become a global leader as a smart contract blockchain it will need to scale to meet the requirements of handling hundreds of millions of users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-scaling-situation">Current Scaling Situation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hydra is the leading project being executed by IOG to help Cardano scale the blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first phase of Hydra will be available in 2022 however this initial implementation will not resolve all of the problems needed for Cardano to scale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sebastien from dcSpark recently discussed the importance of rollups and alternative solutions in an interview -&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4DslvkLop04" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="need-for-more-scaling-options">Need for more scaling options&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To reach true decentralization the Cardano community will need to not rely on the input from IOG as much as it does now as we move into the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hydra will only have it&amp;rsquo;s initial implementation released early next year. Cardano faces potential scaling problems in 2022 as high demand protocols in DeFi, NFTs and gaming begin and continue being released. With alternative scaling solutions not in place there is a risk of overloading demand on the main chain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="types-of-proposals-encouraged">Types of proposals encouraged&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Proposers should consider new novel ideas or research, extensions of Hydra functionality or porting over solutions used in other blockchains that would be suitable for Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proposers are welcome to focus on market specific scalability solutions - for instance a solution could focus on DeFi specifically with decentralized exchanges (DEX&amp;rsquo;s) as a focus area or other growing markets that could benefit from novel scaling solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scalability topic areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rollups (e.g. zero knowledge rollups, optimistic rollups)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sharding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sidechains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>State channels&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="size-of-proposals">Size of Proposals&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Scaling solutions are inherently complex and require significant engineering effort. As a result proposers should not be discouraged from making proposals that request most of the challenge budget. A single proposal team is both welcome and encouraged to request the entire budget if they can demonstrate an articulated plan with the technical expertise to address the challenge of scaling solutions that are suitable for growing Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="budget-rationale">Budget rationale&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>High technical expertise is needed for scalability solutions. Projects will likely take many months of engineering effort to implement viable solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="follow-on-funding-rounds">Follow on funding rounds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If this this challenge setting gets voted in and the proposal(s) submitted show signs they can be impactful then a follow on challenge will be submitted for fund 9 with a larger requested budget to further help the team(s) be able to request further funding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Community Advisor Improvements</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/community-advisor-improvements/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/community-advisor-improvements/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/21-Community-Advisor-Improvements-dbdbe2.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>100,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/384394">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26453/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Community Advisors are an evolving key role of Project Catalyst and need a place and budget to submit proposals to improve their performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Community Advisors are facing constantly challenges but dont have the possibility to actively co-design their acitivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Community Advisors (CAs) submitting proposals as a Team to improve the CAs performance, activity and evolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of new tools developed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of new mechanisms for assessing and scoring proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of maintenance proposals and groups created&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of out of the box ideas&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Community Advisors (CAs) and Veteran Community Advisors (vCAs) are key players of the current Project Catalyst governance process. They assess proposals and by doing that, provide feedback to proposers to improve their ideas for the next fund, and support voter on deciding which proposals are more ready and have higher chances of being successful and impact the Cardano ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By improving the assessing process, we improve the whole Catalyst process as a consequence. Therefore, this challenge aims at accelerating the evolution of the whole assessing process of Catalyst.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Build new tools to improve (v)CA&amp;rsquo;s work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain general (v)CA resourses, in collaboration with the community and with IOG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluate different models of proposal assessment and scoring&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Develop reputation system(s) for (v)CAs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Develop and assess new remuneration mechanisms for (v)CAs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Cross Chain-Collaboration</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/cross-chain-collaboration/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/cross-chain-collaboration/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/04-Cross-Chain-Collaboration-eb2b89.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>400,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381705">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26436/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How might we create connections and collaboration between Cardano and other blockchains in the next six months?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Interoperability of blockchains and multi-chain awareness guarantees shared success of the cryptoeconomy as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-sucess-look-like">What does Sucess look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Collaborative value creation between Project Catalyst and other communities. Both technical and non-technical initiatives are welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Objective metrics to measure success:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mainnet and testnet transaction volume growth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of proposals including participants from other blockchain communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of technical implementations connecting Cardano to other blockchains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ideas from other chains implemented by Catalyst&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Projects and dApps from other chains implemented on Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Catalyst-created solutions adopted by other chains/communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of events / workshops / sessions arranged with other communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of permanent initiatives with cross-chain teams (members from different blockchain communities together)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The success of Bitcoin spawned numerous off-shoot experiments and the arrival of Ethereum increased tribalism. As the number of altcoins grew, unhealthy &amp;ldquo;maximalism&amp;rdquo; emerged. The future is multi-chain, however, and the cryptoeconomy thrives when interoperability and cross-chain collaboration are cherished and encouraged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are multiple next generation blockchains with cadres of zealous supporters, highly skilled developers and innovative technologies that Cardano and Project Catalyst can learn from. And, vice versa, we can help other networks thrive by offering the good practices developed in Catalyst. IOG has recently formed the UTXO alliance and started collaboration with numerous partners like COTI and SingularityNET. It&amp;rsquo;s a good start but more is needed to address the lack of communication, coordination and collaboration between blockchain communities. Missing awareness of each other&amp;rsquo;s doings forces us to duplicate our efforts. When we are separate we are not able to learn from each other&amp;rsquo;s achievements or failures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano has a strong, open and inclusive community, let&amp;rsquo;s make this a real super power and let&amp;rsquo;s be the first ones to forge strong bonds. Let&amp;rsquo;s create an enriching, open and safe environment, where people from different communities can find common ground and share knowledge, resources, skills, ideas and visions with one another. Let&amp;rsquo;s go out there, break the silos and build bridges and presence between us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here are some examples of potential DLT/Blockchain entities, communities and projects to explore and collaborate with:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cosmos&lt;/strong>, dubbing itself the Internet of Blockchains, makes it easy for other blockchains to connect to it via their Inter-Blockchain Communication protocol (IBC). Massive projects like Binance Smart Chain, Terra, Thorchain and Oasis Network are built on the Cosmos SDK.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://tendermint.com/sdk/">TenderMint&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://v1.cosmos.network/intro">Cosmos Intro&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cosmos.network/ecosystem/apps">Cosmos Network&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/learn-video-tutorials">Polkadot&lt;/a> (and its canary network &lt;strong>Kusama&lt;/strong>) is a light-weight and quickly updateable design where the Relay Chain offers shared security and cross-chain communication, allowing the connected Parachains to focus on fast deployment of services. Its unique crowdloan mechanism invites the community of token holders to voice out which projects should be implemented first. The Nominated Proof of Stake network offers advanced governance mechanisms as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academically impressive and technologically sound &lt;a href="https://www.algorand.com/technology">Algorand&lt;/a> has a unique consensus mechanism Pure Proof of Stake and we can learn a lot from their governance model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boasting a throughput beyond 4,500 tps and near-instant finality, the EVM-compatible Avalanche has quickly become the go-to choice for multiple DeFi projects. It has an innovative multi-chain architecture that utilizes both DAG and Blockchain technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.avax.network">Avax&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Other examples could be e.g. &lt;a href="https://fantom.foundation/intro-to-fantom">Fantom&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://solana.com/ecosystem">Solana&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.iota.org/">IOTA&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://polygon.technology/get-started">Polygon&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nervos.org">Nervos&lt;/a> or &lt;strong>any community that is ready for multi-chain reality&lt;/strong>. Or the proposal can come from a project / solution built on any of these.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="proposals-you-can-submit-to-this-challenge">Proposals you can submit to this challenge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is an open-ended challenge that welcomes any proposal geared for cross-chain collaboration, co-innovation and interoperability. These can be any community-led projects, initiatives, solutions, tools or services. It could mean for instance:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New technical implementations connecting Cardano to other blockchains and vice versa (SDKs, APIs, bridges etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Governance ideas from other chains implemented as part of the Voltaire road map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Already successful projects expanding from other chains to Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expansion of Cardano-based projects into other chains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oracles and other tools to interpret and interact with cross-chain data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Catalyst-created solutions adopted by other chains and communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Common research, education, outreach and innovation projects with other chains and communities (e.g. podcasts, hackathons, webinars, communication hubs, educational resources)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="challenge-team">Challenge Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are seasoned Catalyst community members and &amp;ldquo;interoperability maximalists&amp;rdquo; who don&amp;rsquo;t believe that any one chain should rule them all.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Filip Blagojević is an active Project Catalyst member since Fund 2, Plutus Pioneer, Atala Pioneer and Emurgo Academy trainee.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tomi Astikainen is a Veteran Community Advisor who has recently written a book for wannabe crypto investors. He is a Senior Ambassador for Acala/Karura and a driver in the Polkadot/Kusama community in Finland.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Felix Weber is an active Project Catalyst member, Cardano Ambassador and initiator/leader of several community led Projects and initiatives.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="our-assessment-of-the-maturity-of-this-proposed-challenge">Our assessment of the maturity of this proposed challenge:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardano technology stack is finally mature enough to start inviting proposals for cross-chain collaboration and interoperability. Our proposed challenge is intentionally left open ended and it welcomes a multitude of different solutions. Worthwhile ideas submitted in this challenge should help grow and improve the Cardano and Catalyst community in the near term (next 6-9 months).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This challenge is therefore aligned with the Fund8 strategic goals:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It helps prepare people to make contributions to the Cardano and Catalyst ecosystem.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It helps turn Cardano into an open source project recognized also beyond our community.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It accelerates the growth and evolution of our developer &amp;amp; app ecosystem by inviting contributions from the rest of the blockchain space.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The budget of $400,000 USD is a moderate 2,5% of the total treasury allocation for Fund8. It should be sufficient to kickstart interoperability and cross-chain collaboration initiatives but might not be enough for any large scale infrastructure projects. Therefore, &lt;strong>we encourage submission of &amp;ldquo;minimum viable&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;proof of concept&amp;rdquo; proposals that do include long-term vision and roadmap but which are initially scoped quite small&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: DApps and Integrations</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/dapps-and-integrations/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/dapps-and-integrations/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/06-Dapps--Integrations-d3b60a.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>2,500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383335">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26438/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What applications will provide the most value for end users in 2022?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Quality Dapps and integrations will increase utility &amp;amp; adoption of Cardano. A broad funding challenge like this encourages more proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Novel and viable applications get built of top of Cardano attracting users. Integrations manage to pull in more adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To assess the challenge we will be asking ourselves: Did our efforts manage to attract users to the platform? Did our efforts result in new, viable applications built on top of Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let an &amp;ldquo;application output&amp;rdquo; and an &amp;ldquo;application transaction&amp;rdquo; be an output and transactions that use the applications&amp;rsquo; script addresses, and an &amp;ldquo;application token&amp;rdquo; be a token that&amp;rsquo;s issued by the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="usage-of-applications-developed-during-the-challenge">Usage of applications developed during the challenge:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application output&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The total volume of Ada involved in application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Total/growth of resource usage by applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of distinct addresses mentioned in application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="if-the-application-uses-tokens">If the application uses tokens:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application tokens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of distinct addresses holding application tokens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Viability of applications developed during the challenge:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the applications are still being developed at the end of 2022?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the applications made a profit for their creators?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the teams which built the applications grew during 2022?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the teams which built the applications built (or plan to build) another application?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cardano is an ecosystem that sets itself apart through its rigorous research and strives to do things correctly. We expect all dApp projects applying for funding to aspire to the highest possible levels of certification. To understand what this refers to and practically means, please watch Charles Hoskinson&amp;rsquo;s video on this topic: &amp;ldquo;DApp certification and Community Curation&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7zcYSQarI0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This challenge is suitable for incorporated technology or blockchain companies and larger projects with competent teams that already have deployed MVPs. Ideally, these are projects that have a proven user base. Projects that satisfy such criteria are welcome to apply for more than $100,000 if that can be justified and clearly budgeted for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For smaller teams (4-5 people) with proven competence, relevant experience and technical skills with sketches/whitepaper detailing how they would go about to launch their proposal, the budgets would typically be in the range $40,000-$80,000.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For people with the relevant background but without a full team or completed whitepaper detailing the solution, the project ought to be considered as a research stage project and budgets should less than $10,000.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What are the key applications that underpin the application ecosystem on other platforms?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the most profitable or most used applications on other ecosystems?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What needs do users of Cardano have that could be solved by new applications?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What applications deliver the highest amount of value with the least amount of technical sophistication?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Swaps, both simple and fancy variants (multi-party etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Escrow, both simple and fancy variants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrations with existing products&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NFT marketplace or facilitator&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solutions utilising the power of smart contracts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Develper Ecosystem</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/developer-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/developer-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/01-Developer-Ecosystem-4d9cc4.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>1,000,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/384822">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26433/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can we create a positive developer experience that helps the developer focus on building successful apps?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Creating an awesome experience that incentives developers, will lead to increased developer adoption, productivity, and creativity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardano has a thriving dev ecosystem, developers are able to scale their businesses by monetizing the services that they provide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Key metric to measure&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves: Did we manage to make it easier for developers to build on top of Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Filling in gaps defined in the exploration stage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of developers actively building on top of Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of repos on Github using the tooling. (Month over month increase)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce wait time of unanswered communications with developers to 24 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A sense of community and conversations. Having people around to talk with&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="guiding-questions">Guiding Questions&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What are the the tools that we need to prioritize first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How do we attract developers from outside of our current community to participate in Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What do developers want, and how do they get it from the Cardano dev ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What would make it a developer motivated to grind through the docs and code no matter how hard it is to create an app?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are enterprise dev managers looking for in order to be able to build out enterprise projects - either internal or commercial?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="potential-directions">Potential Directions&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developer productivity: IDE&amp;rsquo;s, scripts to automate stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knowledge base &amp;amp; Documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deployment, testing, and monitoring frameworks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Samples, recipes and templates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hackathons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DEFI and tokenization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dashboards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API&amp;rsquo;s, and oracles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support structures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incentivization structures&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-does-this-compare-to-the-open-source-development-ecosystem-challenge">How does this compare to the Open Source Development Ecosystem challenge?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The difference is in the title. While we are advocates of open source, we recognize that not all teams are at the point where they feel comfortable or capable of open sourcing their solutions. Some APIs may be closed source forever, but still provide an overall net positive for the Cardano ecosystem. If you are all-in on open source from day one, definitely go with the Open Source Development Ecosystem challenge (if that&amp;rsquo;s an option). We are rooting for you. We believe, however, there&amp;rsquo;s room for both at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Catalyst Town Hall from December 1st 2021 had a breakout room dedicated to this discussion. Once it becomes available it shall be attached as a comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Open-Source-Development-Ecosystem/382213-48088">https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Open-Source-Development-Ecosystem/382213-48088&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Film + Media (FAM) creatives unite!</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/film-and-media-creatives-unite/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/film-and-media-creatives-unite/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/20-Film--Media-FAM-creatives-unite-4e9e0a.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>150,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383633">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26452/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Global entertainment+media market = $2 trillion. A decentralized FAM network to produce quality Cardano community media is vital yet absent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A challenge category for creatives has been absent so far. Diversity + human creativity in the arts can enrich the Cardano ecosystem + more&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Teams collaborating equitably to produce inclusive, high quality multimedia content + platforms = increase knowledge + adoption of Cardano&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As a measure of the health of the ecosystem:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>of multimedia projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of multimedia platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of multilingual teams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of decentralised film crews&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of decentralised news teams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of decentralised content creation teams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>of decentralised multimedia projects sharing resources (eg RAW footage) to avoid unnecessary costs and CO2 emissions from travelling to shoot footage on site&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creatives, writers, artists, filmmakers, photographers +more, collaborating equitably, can enrich the ecosystem with their cultural diversity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano has a strong YouTube community, but obviously YouTube is not everything and it&amp;rsquo;s not received well in many perspectives.
We need a bridge between YouTube, the traditional media, TV and film. We need to communicate a clear message towards media.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to create educational and inspiring content which the national media and TV stations would gladly use in their daily programmes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this early stage, the cooperation between YouTubers and TV &amp;amp; Film professionals is not only welcomed, it&amp;rsquo;s needed.
Creating a specific challenge for this should open the gates for both education and inspiration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Film and Media (FAM) Challenge aims to boost knowledge and adoption of Cardano for global audiences by enabling:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a challenge platform for the facilitation of professionals and creatives to connect, collaborate and coordinate&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>the launch of projects that spotlight the multitude of stories within the Cardano ecosystem&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multimedia projects that illustrate how Cardano&amp;rsquo;s blockchain is the &amp;lsquo;green blockchain&amp;rsquo; solution in a world that needs solutions to the climate emergency&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A dedicated challenge category for this creative group to platform their catalysing ideas has been absent thus far.
This has led to potentially impactful projects struggling to find their place in Challenge categories that are not quite the &amp;lsquo;right fit&amp;rsquo;. The FAM challenge category can unlock a flow of submission of ideas and proposals that bring about high quality, educational and inspirational multi-lingual multi-media content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Content that helps build bridges within the Cardano ecosystem and across multi sectoral ecosystems, globally. So FAM creatives, in all corners of the world, step up. You are the ones we have been waiting for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Gamers On - Chained</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/gamers-on-chained/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/gamers-on-chained/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/08-Gamers-On-Chained-82871b.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381329">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26440/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What Blockchain gaming applications should be developed to achieve mass adoption of Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Gamers are ready to enter crypto. They just need a clear blockchain with enjoyable applications to engage on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardano becomes the go to blockchain to develop gaming applications due to its quality tooling and wide gamer centric user base.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Key Metrics to measure&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Total users of gaming based applications built on Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of gaming based applications building/built on Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amount of value made by gamers in play-to-earn applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of CNFTs made specifically for gaming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of fungible tokens made specifically for gaming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of gaming based content creators that have come to Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of gaming tournaments hosted for Cardano native assets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of proposals submitted to this challenge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amount of comments and kudos given to submitted proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amount of ADA voted on proposals in this challenge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amount of Wallets voted on proposals in this challenge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amount and evolution of gaming based tokens and wallets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We need to increase brand awareness of Catalyst amongst the entrepreneur gaming community and propose a way for gamers to be onboarded into the Cardano ecosystem through the thing they love, gaming. These proposals can take the form of building out a Cardano based game, a dev tool or SDK for Cardano based game development, a blockchain layer that integrates with existing games, or anything else that prioritizes gamers or game developers as its end user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 2.5 billion gamers out there. These gamers are looking for their route into crypto in a fun and rewarding way. Let&amp;rsquo;s provide them a library of games and integrations to choose from, solidifying Cardano as the go to blockchain for gaming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets on-chain these gamers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Grow Africa, Grow Cardano</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-africa-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-africa-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/10-Grow-Africa-Grow-Cardano-1daa76.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>250,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/384227">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26442/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we continue to seed and grow Cardano in Africa in 2022?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &amp;lsquo;Grow Africa&amp;rsquo; challenge is central to a key initiative of Cardano&amp;rsquo;s, expanding into Africa. Allow Catalyst to also support this drive.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardano is the blockchain of choice in Africa by 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Projects and developers in Africa will not be isolated, but networked and growing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of new African projects seeded in 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals clearly demonstrate Cardano tech use-case solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of African developers onboarded in 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local impact (measurable through user activity and reach)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local partnerships formed (size of institution + influence)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>*&amp;ldquo;Having a funding round that focuses on Africa is a win, win, win scenario. Africa wins by getting some backing. Commercial projects that are already building up in Africa win, because they get the signal of support from our community. Cardano holders win when there is an encouraging environment for mass adoption anywhere.*Focussing on Africa is a strategy that has often been promoted and is openly pursued by IOG and Charles Hoskinson. The ROI is likely to be high because community sponsored projects are better run in young and developing economies.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>Greg Bell; (originator of the Grow Cardano series)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout human history and civilization, it has been that every few centuries or so a confluence of factors align to transition us from one phase of development to another; The first and second industrial revolutions are prime examples. Right now we are barely out of the Web2 revolution and a fourth Industrial revolution or Web3 is upon us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although Africa did not play a key role in the first, second or third industrial revolution, it is poised to be a leader in Web 3.0 technology and those with foresight are positioning themselves strategically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cardano community can be one of these visionaries. Let&amp;rsquo;s be serious about seeding long term projects in Africa to capture a large share of an important emerging market.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rationale-for-budget">Rationale for budget&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s be frank here. We need much more than 250k to continue seeding Cardano in Africa. We are asking for this amount because of Catalyst voting patterns; in that $250k is better than $0 and Wada and Partners can still take advantage of other challenge categories to help expand Cardano in Africa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Grow East Asia, Grow Cardano</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/12-Grow-East-Asia-Grow-Cardano-c2a227.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>150,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/382067">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26444/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we grow the Cardano ecosystem in East Asia in an inclusive and supportive way? The same way we do in Africa, focused initiatives!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Cardano community leans heavily toward North America and Europe. Growth elsewhere requires our support and initiative as a community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A broad spectrum of people across Asia and connected to Asia, coming together and forming teams to grow our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves some questions about the quality of participation:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of proposals originating from East Asian participants in Project Catalyst&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The quantity and quality of funded proposals originating from East Asian teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The observed impact of funded projects (meeting their KPIs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did we increase the participation of the Cardano community and Catalyst teams with East Asian residents?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Was there an increase in Daily/Monthly Active Wallets (DAW/MAW) as a proxy measure of momentum and engagement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did we increase the number of Stake Pools and Stake Pool Operators based in East Asia?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will also be asking some specific questions about the quality of the proposals:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there good feedback on funded project progress, failure or success, that help us understand the nuances of deploying Cardano solutions across East Asia?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the novelty and appropriateness of solutions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are we on track to improve the lives of people using Cardano in East Asia?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Was social and environmental impact evaluation used to measure proposal performance?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the sustainability of proposals beyond the scope of Catalyst?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As in Africa, raising the awareness levels of regular people in East Asia about blockchain and the Cardano network should be a priority for the Catalyst community. In this challenge, we provide funding for people who have learned about Cardano to take advantage of the community&amp;rsquo;s support and build on or use the Cardano network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The nature of the proposals for this challenge is open-ended. Their only requirement is to originate or focus on East Asia and include east Asian team members or focus on East Asian participants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, the overwhelming majority of Stake Pools reside in North America and Europe. The Cardano network will be more resilient when Stake Pools are evenly distributed across the globe. The Catalyst community needs to step up and intentionally make that happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano started life in East Asia (Japan and Hong Kong), and Emurgo focuses on East Asia. Let&amp;rsquo;s build upon that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What this is:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A call to action; Activate the Cardano community&amp;rsquo;s ability to recognise, reward the opportunity to make the world a better place. East Asia is fertile ground for the adoption of Cardano. The return on intention (ROI) is likely to be high because projects in young and developing economies face less economic inertia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addressing different parts of the world directly and intentionally through funding challenges makes our community more accessible. It makes us more resilient. It helps us learn and understand the needs of communities that make up our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a vision that needs votes to become an achievement. When the challenge succeeds, the beneficiary is the whole Cardano community. It is a call to close our prejudices and open our eyes, hearts and minds to good people who lack the benefits many of us were born with—allowing others with fewer privileged circumstances to rise and succeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Grow India, Grow Cardano</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-india-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/grow-india-grow-cardano/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/22-Grow-India-Grow-Cardano-82a925.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>150,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381216">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26454/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can we grow Cardano development and adoption in India?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>1.4B people. 55% under 30y (2016 est)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Local Cardano developers/businesses needed to solve local issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Significant poverty/unbanked&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Success is having multiple submissions for Catalyst Fund8 for India focused projects, with real-world projects getting funded and built.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The overall key metrics would be:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Increased interaction between Catalyst and Indian focused projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Indian focused Catalyst submissions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Indian focused dapps/services actually built&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As well as Africa, I think we should also put significant focus on Cardano within India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>India has a massive population of 1.4 billion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>55% are under the age of 30yrs (Wikipedia, 2016 est.) There are a significant percentage of unbanked/rural people worldpoverty.io notes 100 million Indians (7%) live in extreme poverty Certain rural areas are already using Aadhaar Pay to pay for goods using their fingerprint see &lt;a href="https://www.payaadhar">https://www.payaadhar&lt;/a>. In 2019). So there is enough infrastructure and consumer devices in place to make this a serious market right away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having an India focused Catalyst challenge/fund would be very useful to gather teams and ideas and get the Cardano ball rolling in India. I am not Indian and have no connection to India, but I think that Cardano could be useful to help solve issues that they face and also to grow the Cardano eco-system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the surface issues in India might appear similar to Africa or South America, and there will be some overlap, but ideally local people identifying and solving local issues is best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emurgo has an office in India, but not sure what they are up to. IT in India is well established with a large pool of talent and skills available - we need to let them know about Cardano and the Catalyst funding. This proposal is intended to focus on India within a Fund8 challenge, with that challenge attracting actionable proposals to grow the community of developers and educators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some suggestions for that Fund8 challenge are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Setting up local Cardano hubs for regular catch ups (virtual or real world)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Local-language websites/socials/YT set up to attract developers/entrepreneurs to explain Cardano and Catalyst at a high-level&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fund a dapp and create a how-to video in local-language as a walk through to help educate and reduce perceived complexity&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run a competition/pitch-fest for dapp ideas with the top 10 ideas get funded to make a MVP&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Connect with universities and training centers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Connect with new and established Indian YouTube channels to talk Cardano tech, dev ideas, business opportunities etc to create a buzz about Catalyst funding&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Regularly promote awareness of Cardano and Catalyst funding to bring people into the space eg a 12 month campaign&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is like a big heavy wheel that will take a lot of energy to get turning, but once it starts to move it will (hopefully) keep going with less energy needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much ADA/USD should be available for this proposal?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it will take a few Catalyst rounds to build the Cardano interest in India, so the first round of investment during Fund8 should be $150k. Subsequent funding rounds can be determined at the time and then voted on by the community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Improve and Grow Auditability</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/improve-and-grow-auditbility/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/improve-and-grow-auditbility/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/15-Improve-and-Grow-Auditability-5955cb.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383480">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26447/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How to make the auditing process of funded proposals efficient, distributed and transparent?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s important that the funded proposals are evaluated to see if they are delivering what was established in their mission..&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Several projects evaluating funded proposals, providing reports, articles and metrics on the development and implementation of the projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of funded proposals audited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Considering that the idea is to audit and report on the development of proposals in different challenges, it is important that - - - success metrics are thought out in relation to each challenge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of reports, articles and videos/podcasts on:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Achievements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Financials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of onboarded developers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of commits in funded proposal repositories (Github)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Indicators of: transactions, volume and unique wallets interacting with dapps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of smart contracts audited.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social media engagement indicators.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When Fund7 happens we will be close to 300 funded proposals. It is extremely important that these proposals are evaluated/audited to see if they are delivering and if the ROI is being in line with what has been established initialy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, IOG is in charge of monitoring the development of these funded proposals, but when there are hundreds of funded proposals this will be an overwhelming work for IOG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Auditability challenge aims to ensure transparency in the use of Cardano&amp;rsquo;s treasury resources, which will allow the Cardano community to have more information on the development of funded proposals through a checks and balances system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Lobbying for favorable legislation</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/lobbying-for-favorable-legislation/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/lobbying-for-favorable-legislation/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/14-Lobbying-for-favorable-legislation-38d3c1.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>300,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381094">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26446/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can we defend ourselves from attacks by governments and compromising legislation and unfair tax policies on an ongoing basis?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So that we have favorable legislation, privacy, tax reduction, and a positive environment for mass adoption of cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-sucess-look-like">What does Sucess look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We managed to delay or reverse legislation that compromises crypto adoption and support local communities and organizations like Coincenter&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of jurisdictions favored through lobbying&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of laws that have been modified&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of experts in regulation, lawyers, and other members involved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of partnerships and collaborations with organizations and non-profits that work in the same cause&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of votes of politicians engaged&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The idea behind this challenge is to fund specialists in regulation, lawyers, and politicians who can promote the creation of an environment of laws that are more favorable or less harmful to the crypto space, with a focus on PoS and on Cardano&amp;rsquo;s particularities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this challenge, we can fund proposals that seek the adoption of Cardano in certain jurisdictions, as happened recently with Bitcoin in El Salvador.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2021/09/07/bitcoin-now-legal-tender-in-el-salvador-marking-world-first">https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2021/09/07/bitcoin-now-legal-tender-in-el-salvador-marking-world-first&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lobby and educate rational politicians so that it becomes possible to plead for the creation of more favorable rules on taxation, use of cryptocurrencies, and greater privacy for cryptocurrency users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In August 2021, the US Senate voted for unforgiving legislation on the crypto ecosystem. We have few voices to defend our community in the political class. Initiatives like the Coin Center are important to defend our community. How can we defend ourselves from attacks by authoritarian governments and compromising legislation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/4avpp3/cryptocurrency-lost-big-in-senate-infrastructure-bill-provision-now-what">https://www.vice.com/en/article/4avpp3/cryptocurrency-lost-big-in-senate-infrastructure-bill-provision-now-what&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Miscellaneous Challenge</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/miscellaneous-challenge/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/miscellaneous-challenge/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/09-Miscellaneous-Challenge-db88cb.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381326">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26441/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we create a space for ideas and projects that do not fit any of the other current Challenges?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Creating a Miscellaneous Challenge could enable great ideas to be funded in a specific Fund, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t fit any other Challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Funding great ideas that focus on problems that are not covered by any other Challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves: was this challenge valuable to the community?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Successfully fund proposals, approved by the community, that don&amp;rsquo;t fit well any other challenges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of identified possible Challenges to be proposed in the following Funds based on proposals submitted in the Miscellaneous Challenge.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This challenge is designed to capture interesting and valuable projects that do not currently fit into other challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only constrain to submit a proposal in this challenge is that the proposal needs to be somehow related to Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="defining-the-challenge-alignment">Defining the challenge Alignment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the assessment stage, Community Advisors should evaluate if proposals submitted in this challenge would be a good fit in any of the other existing challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this is the case, i.e., there is another challenge where the proposal would be well aligned with the challenge goals, then this proposal is not so well aligned with the &amp;lsquo;Miscellaneous Challenge&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Nation Building Dapps</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/nation-buidling-daaps/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/nation-buidling-daaps/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/03-Nation-Building-Dapps-b80970.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>800,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383828">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26435/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What core Nation Building Dapp solutions can be provided for widespread users acquired in the developing world?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the poor nations with no basic foundations, Nation Building Dapp solutions will be the building blocks enabling sustainable prosperity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Increasing Dapp usage in developing nations, in collaboration with Cardano Local Community Centers and Intl Partnerships to serve its people&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals CA ratings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Diversity of Dapp&amp;rsquo;s use cases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposers commercial approach and negotiation strategy with different Governments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participation of Cardano&amp;rsquo;s Local Community Centers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participation and/or partnerships with other international organizations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of countries covered, contracts signed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Dapp users, registry accounts, transaction volumes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposers lead time on field research, Dapp development and implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dapps impact on social/financial inclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dapps impact on economic development&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the poor nations with no foundations to stand on, Nation Building Dapp solutions will be the building blocks enabling sustainable prosperity. The 2017 Findex report shows that about a quarter of unbanked adults live in the poorest 20 percent of households in their country. Proposals in Nation Building Dapps will be able to help provide digital identities to these people and help them out of poverty. We want to encourage Cardano blockchain solutions that will be able to provide nations with decentralized solutions to their infrastructure by eliminating a single point of failure, protecting national, corporate, and individual data, property, and assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://globalfindex.worldbank.org/sites/globalfindex/files/chapters/2017%20Findex%20full%20report_chapter2.pdf">https://globalfindex.worldbank.org/sites/globalfindex/files/chapters/2017%20Findex%20full%20report_chapter2.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dapp proposals should cover foundational Registry solutions, namely:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National ID &amp;amp; Civil Registry, Property Registration, Medical &amp;amp; Vaccination, Education Census, Revenue Service, Business Incorporations, Elections Voting, Customs &amp;amp; Border Control, Criminal Records, Employment Census, Vehicle Registration, Licensing &amp;amp; Certifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proposers to review IOHK/ EMURGO Atala Prism solutions before hand along with reference use cases on integrated registry systems applications currently implemented across wealthy nations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it is further advised Proposers to obtain a knowledge base over research done in the past three decades unraveling the &amp;ldquo;mysterious&amp;rdquo; causes of poverty in third world countries by the economist Hernando de Soto. The attached book, &amp;ldquo;The Mystery of Capital,&amp;rdquo; is a great reference to get into context for anyone involved in developing proposals for this challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*&lt;em>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> Think of government as from the people, for the people and by the people.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="introduction-video">Introduction Video&lt;/h4>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WaDP0n4pV84" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: New Member Onboarding</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/new-member-onboarding/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/new-member-onboarding/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/18-New-Member-Onboarding-16fc23.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/382639">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26450/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How might we make it faster and easier for new Catalyst members to take on suitable roles and responsibilities in 2022?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The success of Catalyst depends on the availability of quality challenge teams, proposers, advisors, mentors and voters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A well-oiled open innovation platform where people fulfill roles that are meaningful for them and that contribute to shared success.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The metrics can be divided to two sections. General onboarding refers to bringing people in and converting them from mere lurkers to voters and potential proposers. Innovation process metrics refer to the quantity and quality of proposals and activity around them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="general-onboarding">General onboarding&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Weekly sign ups to Cardano Ideascale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Townhall attendance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Catalyst School session attendance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Swarm session attendance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applications to leadership positions (e.g. Circle)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="innovation-process">Innovation process&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of referrers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduction in the number of unready proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Growtn in the number of 4-5 star proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Growth in the number of Community Advisors and Veteran Community Advisors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Percentage of proposals with Excellent assessments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Growth in the number of voters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Growth in total number of votes given&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The growth of Project Catalyst depends on meaningful participation from proposers, advisors, mentors and voters who are both eager and capable to fulfill their roles and understand their responsibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How might we convert passive ADA holders into active Catalyst members?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How might we increase awareness of Project Catalyst as the most active open innovation platform?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How might we increase more meaningful participation from challenge teams, proposers, advisors, mentors and voters? What kind of additional roles are needed?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How might we encourange new members to utillize the tools and services availalbe for onboarding?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How might we improve the use of existing text, video and audio materials?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Open Source Development Ecosystem</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/open-source-development-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/open-source-development-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/02-OS-Developer-Ecosystem-603bcd.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>1,200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/382213">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26434/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can we ensure that the Cardano ecosystem is built on a framework which is owned by the community and equally accessible to all?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We need to grow an entire ecosystem of experts to build and maintain the foundations of Cardano/Catalyst together with the current IOG teams&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A growing number of experts join forces to build collaboratively on community owned infrastructure, tooling, standards, libraries and docs&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>increase the number and the quality of Cardano Open Source projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>increase the number of contributors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>increase of open source tools and frameworks from the community for the community (dog-fooding)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the first iterations, Catalyst started as a Challenge proposed by the Catalyst team. Initially, the majority of its budget was destined to the Developer Ecosystem. For instance, in Fund 6, the Developer Ecosystem was assigned 1 mil. USD, that was 25% of the total 4 mil. available for the Fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Fund 7, Catalyst released control of the budget to the community, which was able to choose the destination of the funding through voting. Unfortunately, the Developer Ecosystem challenge proposed for F7 was rejected because it did not receive enough votes. This led to the lack of an important resource stream that could have been used for the development of the Cardano technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="open-source-development-ecosystem-challenge">Open Source Development Ecosystem challenge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The OSDE challenge aims to provide a stream of resources to teams that want to develop their projects and contribute back to the community by sharing part of their efforts in terms of open source projects, open-source frameworks, and accessible knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main idea is that projects funded by the community can both generate business value retained by the teams, and at the same time contribute back to the community by improving the ecosystem itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, a team can be funded to develop a project; generate business value by leveraging a profitable idea, and share the non-core-business part of their work in terms of shared knowledge or in terms of building frameworks or projects with other teams - such that is possible to solve complex problems by joining minds and dividing the efforts across different teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation">Motivation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Catalyst exists to gradually work towards the final stage of the roadmap of Cardano: Voltaire. We are building tools to support new forms of governance and collaboration, on top of technology that is still being developed. The development of this technology itself, in the end, will have to become part of this same process as well. Such a complex and daunting task requires experts from a variety of disciplines to work together with a common goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How can we ensure future efforts benefit from the work that is funded today?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How do we align between different open source community efforts?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the next steps to fuse IOG development with the community?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we encourage experts to collaborate and share their knowledge and work?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we develop a sustainable ecosystem while sharing knowledge and efforts?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="possible-directions">Possible directions&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Education for development in the Cardano &amp;amp; Catalyst ecosystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing common tools, frameworks, core infrastructures, or proof of concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incentive systems for development &amp;amp; hosting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Common audited repositories &amp;amp; overviews of existing solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organizing events to bring the development ecosystem together&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaboration to improve interoperability within the ecosystem&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Open Standards &amp; Interoperability</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/open-standards-and-interoperability/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/open-standards-and-interoperability/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/17-Open-Standards--Interoperability-ea2841.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/383619">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26449/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Can we build an Open Ecosystem to drive growth, give equal opportunities to all, and increase the synergies across Cardano projects?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To deliver complex software, driving collaboration, and accelerating innovation by sharing identity, practices, and sw components/services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A vendor-neutral ecosystem to&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>drive growth, awareness, discoverability&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>increase commercial adoption&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>provide needed infrastructures&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open standards&lt;/strong> adoption should increase among cardano projects. On the long term, all of the community-funded projects should be open and transparent by following common standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There should be &lt;strong>observable improvements&lt;/strong>: easier to discover projects and find project resources, more intuitive to access project knowledge base (documentation, how-to, etc.), and simple to find and contact project members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It should be possible to have &lt;strong>project synergies&lt;/strong> by allowing simple inter-project communication, knowledge sharing, and re-use of existing components/services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We should observe an &lt;strong>increase in open-source contributions&lt;/strong> to different projects: both from new joiners and from other people already in the Cardano community&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We should observe an &lt;strong>increase in reputability&lt;/strong> of the Cardano Open Source projects. The measure can be done by looking at media communications of various open source communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open standards&lt;/strong> built on the principles of openness, transparency and consensus lay the grounds for innovation, growth and fair competition. &lt;em>&lt;strong>Open standards are not synonymous of open source.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> [OPSTD]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We look at Open Source as the best way to enable interoperability between different technologies and applications. But in the Cardano Ecosystem we have a set of open source projects that have no standards for basic cross-project integration. For instance, there are no standards on how to document, set-up, and contribute-to projects. Moreover, there is no common infrastructure that the projects can use to track issues, and publish basic public information about the projects funded by the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are of the advise that we need a set of standards, processes, and infrastructures to be used by the Cardano open source projects, such that (1) The teams of different O.S. projects can easily collaborate; (2) New-joiners can easily discover, understand, test, and contribute to existing O.S. projects; (3) Cardano O.S. projects can access a pool of basic infrastructures and tools that are needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivations">Motivations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As mentioned by Charles Hoskinson &amp;ldquo;Cardano code is Open Source, but needs to be managed like a true open source project, like Linux and other O.S. projects&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T88_XKzi8ms" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In order to proceed in this direction, we need to use Catalyst as a governance over a true, vendor-neutral open source and open-standards ecosystem. To achieve that, we are missing processes (e.g. how the project teams should behave and participate in the ecosystem), and infrastructures (e.g. VCS, CMS, Wiki, Forum, etc.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How can we guide the growth of a vendor neutral ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we build a common identity and increase awareness on Cardano projects?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we increase the discoverability and the commercial adoption of our projects?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we increase the degree of collaboration across different projects?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we lower the barriers and increase open participation to our ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we provide equal opportunities to all projects no matter the size?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="possible-directions">Possible directions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Incentivize collaboration across projects to solve complex problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduce common standards and processes and incentivize their adoption across projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide cross-project infrastructures and tools needed to co-ordinate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure the existence of a cohesive knowledge base&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support a network of professional technology ambassadors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="note">Note&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This challenge builds on top of the existing F7 Open Source Developer Ecosystem and is loosely related to F8 Open Source Development Ecosystem (&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Open-Source-Development-Ecosystem/382213-48088">https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Open-Source-Development-Ecosystem/382213-48088&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, this challenge is about establishing standards, processes, and fostering interoperability across O.S. projects, while the &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; challenges are more focused on growing the O.S. ecosystem by seed-funding open source projects for future challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shortly said: This challenge is about opennes, standardization, and interoperability across open source projects funded by the community, while the &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; one is about increasing the number/quality of projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="references">References&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;code>OPSTD&lt;/code> Almeida, Fernando &amp;amp; José, Oliveira &amp;amp; José, Cruz. (2011). Open Standards And Open Source: Enabling Interoperability. International Journal of Software Engineering &amp;amp; Applications. 2. 10.5121/ijsea.2011.2101.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Scale-UP Cardano's Community Hubs</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/scale-up-cardanos-community-hubs/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/scale-up-cardanos-community-hubs/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/07-Scale-UP-Cardanos-Community-Hubs-f2a538.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/381022">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26439/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we encourage Local Community Hubs to drive adoption and awareness of Cardano in 2022?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Without users on the ground level, we are building niche products serving mostly technical people with blockchain expertise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Local Community Hubs across the world where the average person can take part in their own language and with their own cultural understanding&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How many new Hubs were launched in 2022?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many developers did this community-focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many new users of Cardano were onboarded?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What was the total reach of the Hub&amp;rsquo;s initial marketing launch?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many external organizations did this community-focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Challenge Updates&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Top 3 Challenge Category in Fund 7&lt;/strong> by number of submissions (see attached).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2x Funded Challenge Setting Proposal&lt;/strong> (Fund 5 and Fund 6)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;u>A selection of past-funded &amp;lsquo;Scale-Up Hubs&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/u>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/367891-48088">Homeless Hubs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/367936-48088">Cardano in South L.A&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/367293-48088">Cardano in Buenos Aires&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/368369-48088">Salmon Nation Hub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="what-this-means">What this means&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Demand is growing for this category and we are only at the beginning of what is possible with a network of Cardano hubs globally. The network effect will take a hold at some point and when it does, we need to be ready with templates, guides and materials on creating and sustaining a new Cardano Community Hub (CCH).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The impact is real and ROI is being met. Real lives are being affected and improved through this category. This creates a win-win, positive feedback loop as more people benefit from the solutions we offer them, there is even more demand for these services worldwide.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="how-if-the-fund-8-challenge-different">How if the Fund 8 challenge different?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While the growing demand is showing us that the need is there, our focus for the next challenge should be on the other side of the coin. &lt;strong>Capital supply.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the facts have proven the necessity of a Community Hubs challenge, there are many other equally as important challenges vying for a position in Fund 8, so we must act accordingly. &lt;strong>We must make budget requests that allow others to also pursue their goals&lt;/strong> within the ecosystem, both macro, for Catalyst and micro, within the Challenges themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we are &lt;strong>Scaling UP community hubs&lt;/strong>, we need to &lt;strong>Scale DOWN individual capital outlay&lt;/strong>, to ensure that we can spread as far as possible, as quickly as possible, which is why we work from first principles.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Delivering information to people who would not otherwise have the access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensuring resilience and self-reliance within that community.
When we approach hubs from the lens of information-delivery nodes, we can build a hub taxonomy within a need-impact matrix and then find the most capital efficient model for each location.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In simpler terms, consider why a hub exists, in the context of it&amp;rsquo;s location, access to infrastructure and community readiness. Then design a hub according to those factors, with a traditional brick-and-mortar (CTH) being only one out of many potential information-delivery systems within a local community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This round will focus much more on &amp;lsquo;minimum-viable hubs&amp;rsquo; (MVHs)&lt;/strong>, what is the smallest effective unit for a hub, and by identifying this unit, can we begin to scale CCHs more rapidly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Additional Success Metrics:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Is the hub&amp;rsquo;s Fund 8 proposal in keeping with the MVH principle?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do they have an understanding of their target audience?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can they accurately project their reach (physical and online) in the first 3, 6, 12 months?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can they accurately project the number of onboarded members to the hub in 3, 6, 12 months?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have they given an indication of a financial sustainability model?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have they given an indication of budget costs vs &amp;lsquo;cost to launch&amp;rsquo;? (eg. A CTH may only apply for 1/5 of their cost to launch due to the demand pressures of acquiring catalyst funding)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Ratings by CAs and Voters should favour:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Proposals that have a budget:cost-to-launch ratio between 1-1.5.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals that do not exceed 5% of the total Challenge budget.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals that account for local needs and infrastructure concerns.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals that show creativity and ingenuity around hub design and information delivery.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proposals that are using local, recyclable materials and have a commitment to sustainability practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Let&amp;rsquo;s build an ecosystem that is truly global&lt;/strong>, allowing everyone to participate to the best of their ability, whatever level they are starting from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you &lt;strong>drive adoption at the ground level&lt;/strong>, you are doing more than just &amp;lsquo;building cool products&amp;rsquo;, you are &lt;strong>empowering people to change their lives&lt;/strong> in ways they could have never imagined by themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/bZQvrLI.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/MWddZex.gif" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="extra-reading-where-we-are-going">Extra reading (where we are going):&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/sellafield-invests-26m-to-create-cumbria-business-hub">Cumbria, UK Business Hub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/03/norrsken-foundations-hub-opens-in-rwanda-to-house-1000-entrepreneurs-by-next-year">Rwanda Business Hub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="past-funded-challenges">Past-funded challenges:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Scale-UP-Cardano-s-Community-Hubs/369413-48088">Scale-UP Community Hubs (F6)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Scale-UP-Cardano-s-Community-Hubs/352534-48088">Scale-UP Community Hubs (F5)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Self-Sovereign Identity</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/self-sovereign-identity/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/self-sovereign-identity/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/19-Self-Sovereign-Identity-b0f073.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>400,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/380986">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26451/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How can we take the next step to support the principles of self-sovereign identity?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have the potential to be leaders in the SSI ecosystem, assuring trust and giving individuals control of their digital identities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Receiving high quality projects; growing participation on SSI discussions; partnering with ecosystem, governance and working groups&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The number of proposals that directly address SSI in a quantifiable manner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The quality of proposals measured by community interest and engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Awareness of Cardano inside the SSI community, working groups and governance entities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Catalyst Project by its Fund 6 and Fund 7 has promoted projects that push adoption of the Decentralized Identity and Atala Prism SDK. Additionally, a first cohort was part of the Atala PRISM Pioneer Program and a second one is ready to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The amount and quality of projects proposed so far and the involvement of the community in the matters of Decentralized Identity are clear indicators that &lt;strong>Cardano is ready to make the big move to cope with all aspects of the Self-Sovereign Identity ecosystem.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This challenge is looking for projects that help position Cardano as one of the leaders in the SSI space. With a broader scope than past challenges, we expect this one to tackle all layers defined by the Trust over IP Foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-directions-that-projects-can-take-are">Some directions that projects can take are:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Participation and adoption growth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Portability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Usability and accessibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Governance frameworks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Interoperability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Privacy and minimal disclosure (Zero Knowledge Proofs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regulation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Business models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NFT and Smart Contracts integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trust registries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Equity and inclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Philosophical implications&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: The Great Migration (from Ethereum)</title><link>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/the-great-migration-from-ethereum/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund8/challenges/the-great-migration-from-ethereum/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://cardano.ideascale.com/community-library/accounts/93/936143/Public/16-The-Great-Migration-from-Ethereum-76ace0.png" style="width:500px;height500px">
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>500,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/382642">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/campaigns/26448/stage/all/ideas/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How might we make it easy and fast for dApps and other projects to expand or completely move from Ethereum to Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Many projects are stuck on EVM-based blockchains like Ethereum and are looking for an escape. Cardano can be faster and cheaper to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-success-look-like">What does success look like?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Projects who were either planning to or did launch on an EVM-based blockchain deploy in the Cardano ecosystem and can do so easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of projects that migrate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of users of these smart contracts once migrated to the Cardano ecosystem&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>(Metrics can either be improved by funding projects that directly deploy something, or projects that help build tooling to make it easier to deploy)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Cardano ecosystem, despite being written in Haskell, has always had plans to provide a path for projects that either deployed on an EVM-based blockchain (like Ethereum) to migrate to the Cardano ecosystem. Additionally, projects that are better suited for the account-style method (instead of UTXO) also exist, and we want these projects to be usable from the Cardano ecosystem as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To accomplish this part of the roadmap, many efforts are currently underway such as KEVM, IELE, ERC20 Converter and Milkomeda to name a few. These projects are reaching the point where they are mature enough for people to deploy using them or build tooling for them and so it&amp;rsquo;s time to start welcoming projects to Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can hear Charles talk about the importance of this in his video &amp;ldquo;The Island, The Ocean and the Pond&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k8a6tX53YPs" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>